Guide to the Sarah Browning papers, 1985-2018 MS2252
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Sarah Browning literary papers
1985-2018
1997-2017
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Browning, Sarah
MS2252
2.25 Linear Feet
This collection contains poetry, correspondence, book manuscripts, event programs, weekly planners, brochures, conference information, grant proposals, submissions to publications, clippings, and organizational records. The material dates from 1985 to 2018 but the bulk of the material dates from 1997 to 2017. These are the papers and records of the poet and activist Sarah Browning.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement note
Folders are arranged alphabetically
Biographical
Sarah Browning is Co-Director of Split This Rock Poetry Project and DC Poets Against the War. She is the author of Whiskey in the Garden of Eden (The Word Works, 2007) and co-editor of D.C. Poets Against the War: An Anthology (Argonne House Press, 2004). The recipient of an artist fellowship from the DC Commission on the Arts & Humanities, she has also received a Creative Communities Initiative grant and the People Before Profits Poetry Prize. Browning has worked as a community organizer in Boston public housing and as a political organizer for reproductive rights, gay rights, and electoral reform, and against poverty, South African apartheid, and U.S. militarism. She was founding director of Amherst Writers & Artists Institute -- creative writing workshops for low-income women and youth -- and Assistant Director of The Fund for Women Artists, an organization supporting socially-engaged art by women. She has written essays and interviewed poets and artists for a variety of publications.
Taken from http://www.splitthisrock.org/who.html
Immediate Source of Aquisition note
Gift of Sarah Browning, July 2008 (Accession 2008.027) and February 2019 (Accession 2019.007).
Scope and Contents note
This collection contains poetry, correspondence, book manuscripts, event programs, weekly planners, brochures, conference information, grant proposals, submissions to publications, clippings, and organizational records. The material dates from 1985 to 2018 but the bulk of the material dates from 1997 to 2007. These are the papers and records of Sarah Browning, and they reflect her work as a poet and activist. The collection contains drafts and papers related to her first book, Whiskey in the Garden of Eden. The collection contains correspondence and applications for grants, journal publications, and other publications.
Poetry -- 20th century; Protest poetry; Poetry
- Amherst Writers and Artists Workshop, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Art Club poetry contest judging, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Awards and grants, 2003-2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bethesda Literary Arts festival Poetry Contest, 2011-2013 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Book prizes pending, 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bread Loaf, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Clippings, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 2009-2016 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence from journals, 1993-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- DC Commission on the Arts: The Word Works, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Drafts, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Drafts, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Drafts, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Drafts, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Drafts, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Drafts, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Drafts, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Event programs, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Grant from the Community Foundation of the National Capital Region, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Jean Stokan, 1997-2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Lists of poems sent to publications, 1994-2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Massachusetts Cultural Council applications, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- National Endowment for the Arts poetry, 03/2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- National Writers Union DC, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- National Writers Union reading, 04/2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Notes and other papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Poems, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Poetry in publications, 2003-2016 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Poetry in publications, 2015-2018 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Poetry and Lit Bibliographies and poetry form guidelines, circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Poetry contests, 1999-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Presses, 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Prize rejection slips, 1996-2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Publicity, 2011-2018 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Sarah Lawrence College Summer Seminar, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Sending out logistics, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Sisters of the Earth Fundraiser, 05/10/2004-06/22/2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- South Side Dreams draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Submission guidelines, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Vogelstein Foundation, 04/2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Wednesday group, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Weekly planner 2002 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Weekly planner 2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Weekly planner 2004 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Weekly planner 2005 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Weekly planner 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Whiskey in the Garden of Eden, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Whiskey in the Garden of Eden, circa 1999 - circa 2007 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Whiskey in the Garden of Eden - editorial, 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Whiskey in the Garden of Eden - old, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Whiskey in the Garden of Eden - with comments, circa 2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Workshop and retreat, 2011-2017 (Box 5, Folder 7)